<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social computing | Osama Sakhi</title>
    <link>http://sakhi.es/tags/social-computing/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://sakhi.es/tags/social-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>social computing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Osama Sakhi © 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://sakhi.es/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>social computing</title>
      <link>http://sakhi.es/tags/social-computing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The REDUCE Project</title>
      <link>http://sakhi.es/project/reduce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://sakhi.es/project/reduce/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://socweb.cc.gatech.edu/projects/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;REDUCE&lt;/a&gt; project seeks to improve real-time estimation of suicide rates to better enable suicide prevention activities. We&amp;rsquo;ve partnered with the CDC to use historical trends with social media data to forecast future trends week-to-week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the motivations for integrating social media data is the speed at which up-to-date social media can be obtained &amp;ndash; instantly. In contrast, the ground-truth suicide trend data takes nearly two years for the CDC to aggregate and publish, which presents problems for real-time estimation of suicide trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my role in this project, I&amp;rsquo;ve primarily worked on extracting meaninful signals from social media data we&amp;rsquo;ve collected. Most of my time has been spent on the Twitter dataset, which comprises of over 9 million tweets focused around a selected set of keyword phrases related to depression, anxiety, and suicide collected for a 3 year timespan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on creating embeddings of these tweets that would then be aggregated on a weekly basis. These aggregations would then represent the mass of tweets for that week and could then be used as the features &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; with the target variable &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; being the true number of suicide attempts that week (provided by the CDC). With the right embedding, we could train regression models to predict this &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; fairly accurately. This regression model would then serve as one learner in a final ensemble approach which uses models built separately on data from other sources such as CDC suicide data, Google Health data, Reddit language model data, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;approaches&#34;&gt;Approaches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lexicographical-inquiry-and-word-count-bag-of-words&#34;&gt;Lexicographical Inquiry and Word Count + Bag of Words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each tweet, we wanted to create a high dimensional tensor that would represent the contents of this tweet entirely. We decided to use both a Bag-of-Words embedding along with the LIWC scores as the embedding for each tweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Bag of Words model, we tried several &amp;ldquo;flavors&amp;rdquo; to see what would work best to create our vocabulary and embeddings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;vanilla&lt;/code&gt; - Using the top 10k words in the corpus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;deslang&lt;/code&gt; - Using the top 10k words in the corpus after internet slang words were expanded.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ex: In our tweets, the phrase &lt;code&gt;iykyk&lt;/code&gt; would be expanded into the five words &lt;code&gt;if you know you know&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;stopwords&lt;/code&gt; - Removal of the top english stopwords before keeping the top 10 words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;deslang_stopwords&lt;/code&gt; - A combination of the approaches for &lt;code&gt;deslang&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;stopwords&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;document-embeddings&#34;&gt;Document Embeddings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a new direction we are currently exploring. One crucial limitation of the Bag of Words approach is that the model doesn&amp;rsquo;t take into consideration any sentence structure. This could be problematic especially with our task since certain ways of phrasing a set of words could be perceived as either cause for alarm or simply sarcasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see if this limitation has any effect on the final models used to help predict suicide trends, we are looking into embeddings that are designed to capture document-level patterns. These embeddings can capture much more complex semantic relationships which could be invaluable in our task. Some of the models we&amp;rsquo;re looking at right now include &lt;em&gt;doc2vec&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;SBERT&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is ongoing, so we don&amp;rsquo;t have concrete numbers to publish here at this time. However, we have found that the regression models built off of some of the Bag-of-Words embeddings, particularly the &lt;code&gt;stopwords&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;deslang_stopwords&lt;/code&gt; flavors, have shown promising results already, comparable to those we&amp;rsquo;re seeing from ground-truth suicide trend data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
